<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://zilinbian56.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://zilinbian56.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-08-06T18:31:42+00:00</updated><id>https://zilinbian56.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Digital Twins in urban decision science</title><link href="https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/digitaltwin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Twins in urban decision science"/><published>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/digitaltwin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/digitaltwin/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="dt-in-safety">DT in Safety</h2> <blockquote class="block-warning"> <h5 id="research-question">Research Question:</h5> <p>While congestion is easily observed and captured by sensors for traffic operators, what about the driving risks (e.g., near-miss, hard braking) experienced by drivers? Can they leverage this information to improve traffic management?</p> </blockquote> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/crash.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/crash.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/congestion.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/congestion.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Urban mobility management is vital for ensuring efficient movement in cities, improving transportation systems, and enhancing quality of life. However, current strategies often focus on high-level traffic data while overlooking critical safety risks faced by road users, such as driving hazards and road conflicts. Acquiring safety risk information usually relies on vehicle-based sensing devices, such as advanced onboard equipment (OBE) installed in connected and automated vehicles (CAVs), which can capture real-time driving situations like hard braking, acceleration, and near-miss events.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/cav-dashview.gif" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/cav-dashview.gif" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> OBE risk detection in CAVs </div> <p>However, the current implementation of <strong>CAVs</strong> and vehicle-based sensing devices in large-scale transportation systems is still <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">limited</code>. This gap between management perspectives and driver experiences calls for a more integrated approach that addresses both mobility and safety concerns.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/DT-DIMA%20Concept_v2.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/DT-DIMA%20Concept_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A feedback loop that effectively communicates driver-centric information to transportation managers, thereby enabling more informed, driver-aware decision-making in considering not only mobility risks but also safety risks. </div> <p>Enter the <strong>Digital Twin (DT) technology</strong>. A DT creates a virtual model of the physical transportation system, allowing for real-time monitoring, prediction, and optimization. By integrating DTs into urban mobility management, we can bridge the disconnect between traffic oversight and driver safety. My research proposes the DT-based Driver risk-aware Intelligent Mobility Analytics (<strong>DT-DIMA</strong>), a DT-based framework designed to incorporate real-time driver-centric information into decision-making processes.</p> <p>Key innovations of this system include using pan-tilt cameras (PTCs) as cost-efficient sensors, capable of capturing and replicating real-world traffic conditions across large urban networks. This data feeds into predictive models that assess both mobility risks (e.g., traffic flow and speed) and safety risks (e.g., driving hazards), offering a comprehensive view of road conditions.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="dt-in-emission">DT in Emission</h2> <blockquote class="block-tip"> <h5 id="research-question-1">Research Question:</h5> <p>Greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions are typically measured using fixed monitoring stations, providing insights at a regional or macroscopic level. However, emissions vary significantly based on vehicle type, size, model year, and more. So how can we monitor GHG emissions at a high-resolution, granular level and use this data to improve transportation and environmental management?</p> </blockquote> <p>Current approaches to monitoring greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions largely rely on fixed measurement stations, which provide regional or macroscopic data. While useful for broad assessments, these stations fall short in capturing the nuances of emissions at a more granular level. Vehicle emissions can vary greatly depending on factors like vehicle type, size, fuel type, model year, and driving behavior. This variability is critical for understanding the real impact of transportation on air quality, especially in urban areas where traffic conditions are highly dynamic. The current gap lies in the inability to monitor emissions at a high-resolution level, which limits the potential to make informed decisions about local environmental and traffic management.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/dt-emission-0.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/dt-emission-0.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/dt-emission-1.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/dt-emission-1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> GHG simulation picture was referenced to the post: [If New York’s carbon emissions were solid, they’d bury the Empire State Building within a day](https://grist.org/climate-energy/if-new-yorks-carbon-emissions-were-solid-theyd-bury-the-empire-state-building-within-a-day/). </div> <p>High-resolution emission monitoring is essential for bridging this gap. By capturing detailed, real-time data about individual vehicles and their emissions, transportation managers and environmental policymakers can better understand the distribution of pollutants across different areas and times of day. This detailed data can reveal patterns that are invisible at the regional level, such as localized hotspots of high emissions during peak traffic hours or in areas with frequent congestion. Such insights would enable more targeted interventions, such as adjusting traffic flow, optimizing signal timing, or even implementing dynamic emission-based pricing to reduce pollution in critical areas. Moreover, understanding the specific emission profiles of different vehicle types can support more effective policy measures, such as incentivizing the use of cleaner vehicles or updating emissions standards for certain categories of vehicles.</p> <p>Our solution of achieving high-resolution emission monitoring lies in the integration of Digital Twin (DT) technology, AI methods, and smart sensors. Digital twins create a virtual model of real-world transportation networks, allowing for real-time simulation and analysis of traffic and emissions. By leveraging wide-coverage cameras already deployed along urban roads, we use computer vision methods to extract vehicle type, speed, and aggregated link-based traffic flow, estimate their emissions based on characteristics such as type and driving behavior, then we use graph neural networks (GNNs) to scale up to network-level, and feed this data into a digital twin system. This integration provides transportation managers with a real-time, high-resolution view of emissions across the network, enabling them to make informed decisions that improve both traffic flow and air quality. Digital twins, with their capacity for real-time prediction and optimization, offer high-resolutional monitoring information for managing urban mobility and environmental impact simultaneously.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="dt-in-emergency">DT in Emergency</h2> <blockquote class="block-danger"> <h5 id="research-question-2">Research Question:</h5> <p>How can high-fidelity Digital Twin systems, integrating AI and smart sensors, transform traditional emergency management by providing real-time, detailed situational awareness before and during emergencies, thereby enhancing the efficiency and effectiveness of response teams?</p> </blockquote> <p>Man-made disruptions such as major traffic accidents and infrastructure failures similar to the collapse of Baltimore’s Francis Key Bridge in urban areas, particularly in densely populated regions like the New York-New Jersey (NYNJ) region, present substantial challenges for emergency management, leading to severe network-wide congestion, delays, and potentially life-threatening injuries and fatalities. The unpredictable and complex nature of such incidents requires advanced predictive technologies to effectively manage disruptions and mitigate their impact.</p> <p>Traditional emergency response approaches often depend on human reporting or fixed camera feed, which provide limited, point-specific information and fail to capture comprehensive details of the surrounding environment, such as road layouts and real-time traffic conditions that are continuously changing due to the incident dynamics as well as response measures by emergency management crews. These limitations highlight the need for innovative solutions that are capable of providing detailed and comprehensive situational awareness to drastically improve real-time emergency response capabilities.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/nanodt-concept-0.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/nanodt-concept-0.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> NanoDT for emergency management in response to highly disruptive occurrences in urban areas. </div> <p>Digital Twin (DT) technology provides a powerful tool for replicating real-world transportation systems, aiding traffic accident management at both micro and macro levels. DTs have been effective in capturing vehicle trajectories, supporting traffic management, visualizing infrastructure, vehicle movements, and predicting traffic conditions. However, high-fidelity 3D simulations in DTs are underexplored but essential for offering emergency responders comprehensive awareness. To address this, we introduce the Nano Digital Twin (NanoDT), a cost-efficient approach that integrates broad 2D traffic analysis with focused 3D simulations around accident scenes. The proposed NanoDT targets driving risks, pedestrian conflicts, lane data, and spatial details, enabling real-time, detailed visualizations without overloading computational resources. This enhances Transportation Management Centers’ (TMCs) response capabilities, improving safety and infrastructure resilience in complex urban environments.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <video src="/assets/video/nanodt-video-1.mp4" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" autoplay="" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A quick example of cosimulation of CARLA (left) and SUMO (right). </div> <hr/> <h2 id="resources">Resources</h2> <ul> <li> <p><span id="li2024digital">Li†, T., Bian*†, Z., Lei†, H., Zuo†, F., Yang†, Y.-T., Zhu, Q., Li, Z., Chen, Z., &amp; Ozbay, K. (2025). Digital Twin-based Driver Risk-Aware Intelligent Mobility Analytics for Urban Transportation Management. <i>IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems</i>.</span> <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2407.15025">paper</a></p> </li> <li> <p>Tao Li, <strong>Zilin Bian</strong>*, Haozhe Lei, Fan Zuo, Ya-Ting Yang, Quanyan Zhu, Kaan Ozbay.<br/> <strong>“Leveraging Digital Twins and AI for High-Resolution Greenhouse Gas Emission Monitoring in Urban Transportation Networks.”</strong><br/> Details coming soon.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Zilin Bian</strong>*, Haozhe Lei, Fan Zuo, Shuo Zhang, Tao Li, Ya-Ting Yang, Semiha Ergan, Kaan Ozbay.<br/> <strong>“Harnessing Physics-Informed Traffic Prediction and Digital Twin Technology for Next-Generation High-Fidelity Emergency Management in Urban Networks.”</strong><br/> Details coming soon.</p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="digital-twins"/><category term="AI"/><category term="operation"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How does Digital Twin (DT) help the management process in daily urban system? My research aims to answer this question in terms of enhancing travelers' safety, urban sustainability and emergency response.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Urban Smart Sensing</title><link href="https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/smartsensing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Urban Smart Sensing"/><published>2024-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/smartsensing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/smartsensing/"><![CDATA[<p>In today’s data-driven world, transportation researchers are using advanced technologies to tap into the enormous potential of video data for urban management. As the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) notes, this data is being applied to a variety of areas such as system planning, operations, safety monitoring, and infrastructure condition assessments.</p> <p>By combining video data with cutting-edge AI and deep learning methods, we can unlock a new stream of valuable information. This enables cities to become “machine eyes” for real-time insights, allowing us to monitor urban environments with unprecedented detail and precision.</p> <p>Imagine a city equipped with intelligent sensing systems—tracking traffic, detecting congestion points, monitoring safety hazards, and even assessing infrastructure wear and tear—all in real-time. With this automation, we can shift from static datasets to dynamic, continuous flows of information that lead to smarter, faster, and more efficient decision-making.</p> <p>The figure below illustrates how <strong>Urban Sensing Systems</strong> collect and process data from multiple domains, such as pedestrian movement, traffic conditions, parking availability, freight logistics, emergency response, and environmental monitoring. AI-powered video analysis enables these systems to provide actionable insights, empowering city planners and transportation managers to make informed decisions that improve safety, mobility, and quality of life.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/smartsensing-0.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/smartsensing-0.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Multiple usage of traffic sensing in daily urban system. </div> <p>In the realm of urban management, enhancing situational awareness is crucial to improving decision-making processes. My research aims to answer the pressing question:</p> <blockquote> <p>How can existing urban sensors be optimized to enhance situational awareness across large-scale urban systems?</p> </blockquote> <p>By focusing on accuracy, cost-efficiency, and resiliency, my work seeks to push the boundaries of what urban sensing systems can achieve.</p> <p>On the detection side, a deep-learning-based work zone object detection model using a data-centric approach is developed. This method iteratively improves the model’s performance by augmenting a custom training dataset from multiple sources, overcoming the challenge of sparse annotated real-world work zone images. With this in place, I then explore how existing traffic sensors can be effectively deployed to gain real-time traffic information. One focus of my research is on the flexibility of smart sensors. These sensors are often limited by power constraints, forcing a trade-off between data collection duration and accuracy/resolution. To address this, a learning-based framework that strategically determines observation timings for battery-powered devices is developed. This approach reconstructs full data streams from sparsely sampled observations, minimizing performance loss while significantly extending the system’s lifetime.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/smartsensing-1.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/smartsensing-1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> How to use the existing pan-tilt-zoom cameras installed along each intersection to return network-level situational awareness? </div> <p>Another aspect of my research addresses the <strong>underutilization of urban traffic cameras</strong>. While cities often have wide coverage of traffic cameras along road segments and intersections, these cameras are typically only used when nearby accidents occur. Most of the time, they remain idle.</p> <blockquote> <p>How can we transform the underutilized network of urban traffic cameras into a cooperative, real-time, and network-wide traffic sensing system to enhance the overall efficiency of urban traffic monitoring and management?</p> </blockquote> <p>To maximize the utility of these deployed cameras, I developed a <strong>distributed and cooperative framework</strong> that allows them to work together and provide network-wide traffic information. This dramatically enhances the cost-efficiency of existing urban sensing systems.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/smartsensing-2.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/smartsensing-2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> If some of the current sensors go down, can the rest of traffic sensors (no matter what type) work with each other and stay resilent to such malfunction situation? </div> <p>Lastly, my research extends beyond traffic cameras to explore collaboration with other sensing techniques, including pavement-invasive detectors (e.g., inductive loops, magnetometers) and non-pavement-invasive detectors (e.g., microwave radar, ultrasonic sensors). A key question I address is:</p> <blockquote> <p>What happens when some sensors malfunction? Can the remaining sensing systems cooperate to still provide satisfactory performance?</p> </blockquote> <p>My work seeks to build a resilient sensing network where failures in individual sensors do not compromise the overall system’s capability.</p> <h2 id="resources">Resources</h2> <ul> <li>Tao Li, <strong>Zilin Bian</strong>*, Haozhe Lei, Fan Zuo, Ya-Ting Yang, Quanyan Zhu, Zhenning Li, Kaan Ozbay. <strong>Multi-level traffic-responsive tilt camera surveillance through predictive correlated online learning.</strong> Transportation Research Part C: Emerging Technologies 167 (2024): 104804.</li> <li>Tao Li, <strong>Zilin Bian</strong>*, Haozhe Lei, Fan Zuo, Ya-Ting Yang, Quanyan Zhu, Kaan Ozbay.<br/> <strong>“Enhancing Network-Wide Situational Awareness through Passive and Proactive Online Control: A Graph-Based Transformer Approach for Resilient Urban Sensing Systems.”</strong><br/> Details coming soon.</li> <li>Fan Zuo, Jingqin Gao, Kaan Ozbay, <strong>Zilin Bian</strong>, Daniel Zhang. <strong>Urban Work Zone Detection and Sizing: A Data-Centric Training and Topology-Based Inference Approach.</strong> In 2023 IEEE 26th International Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC), pp. 3235-3240. IEEE, 2023.</li> <li>Ruixuan Zhang, Wenyu Han, <strong>Zilin Bian</strong>, Kaan Ozbay, Chen Feng. <strong>Learning When to See for Long-term Traffic Data Collection on Power-constrained Devices</strong> In 2023 IEEE 26th International Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC), pp. 3235-3240. IEEE, 2023.</li> </ul> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="AI"/><category term="operation"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to use existing sensors to enhance the situational awareness of large-scale urban system? My research aims to answer this question in terms of cost-efficiency, resiliency, and accuracy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mobility and Incident Management in Urban Systems</title><link href="https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/mobilitymanagement/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mobility and Incident Management in Urban Systems"/><published>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/mobilitymanagement</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zilinbian56.github.io/blog/2024/mobilitymanagement/"><![CDATA[<p>In our rapidly urbanizing world, ensuring smooth and safe mobility within cities is a complex challenge, made more pressing by the increasing frequency of unexpected disruptions and incidents on the road. My research in urban mobility and incident management focuses on leveraging <strong>spatio-temporal modeling</strong> techniques, by making analogies between <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">road network and its topological elements</code>, to improve real-time, near-future, and long-term situational awareness and response capabilities for urban transportation systems. By developing tools that enable proactive management and resilience in the face of congestion and incidents, I aim to enhance both the safety and efficiency of urban mobility networks.</p> <p>Traffic incidents, such as accidents and work zones, introduce significant challenges to urban transportation systems, often resulting in congestion, delays, and cascading disruptions that affect a wide area. These incidents not only hinder the flow of traffic but also create heightened safety risks, as congestion and delays can increase the likelihood of secondary accidents.</p> <p>My research begins by investigating the impact of traffic incidents on urban transportation systems. For example, I applied Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) and Monte Carlo Dropout to quantify the uncertainty associated with reduced road capacity due to work zones. Expanding to unexpected traffic accidents, I first developed an adaptive Bayesian network method to predict accident duration, providing valuable insights for incident response. Building on this, I designed a stacked autoencoder (SAE) combined with Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) networks to analyze traffic flow patterns influenced by accidents. Recognizing the importance of both spatial and temporal correlations, I then expanded my research to model traffic networks as graphs, effectively capturing how traffic flows propagate along connected road segments. To further enhance temporal understanding, I integrated road capacity data into a Graph Convolutional Network (GCN) paired with a Temporal Convolution Network (TCN), allowing the model to better learn time-dependent traffic dependencies. To further advance prediction capabilities, I developed a Multi-Scale Graph Wavelet Network with Temporal Convolution (MSGWTCN), which leverages graph wavelet properties to continuously adjust its scales during the learning process. This adaptive scaling allows MSGWTCN to effectively capture both short-range and long-range traffic propagation, providing a more nuanced understanding of spatial patterns and temporal sequences.</p> <p>Beyond immediate situational awareness of traffic flow and congestion, my research also explores how traffic incidents might affect traffic in the near future and over the long term. To address this, I designed a data-driven framework that learns from empirical patterns of traffic impacts caused by pre-planned work zones, using machine learning models to provide predictive insights. This framework forecasts the potential impacts of upcoming or scheduled work zones based on planned road closure details and their spatial-temporal characteristics, such as location, start/end time, and duration. The framework has been deployed as a web-based tool, the Data-driven Work Zone Impact and Conflict Estimation platform (<a href="https://c2smarter.engineering.nyu.edu/developing-a-multi-agency-multi-modal-construction-management-software-tool-to-enhance-coordination-of-construction-projects-city-wide-during-planning-and-operation-phases/">DWICE</a>), which is currently utilized by the New York State Department of Transportation (NYSDOT) to support more informed planning and impact mitigation.</p> <h2 id="resources">Resources</h2> <ul> <li><strong>Zilin Bian</strong> and Kaan Ozbay. <strong>Estimating uncertainty of work zone capacity using neural network models.</strong> Transportation Research Record 2673 (2019): 49-59.</li> <li><strong>Zilin Bian</strong>, Kaan Ozbay and Abdullah Kurkcu. <strong>Travel time uncertainty prediction in the presence of non-recurrent traffic congestion.</strong> Accepted in 99th Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board (TRB 2020).</li> <li><strong>Zilin Bian</strong>, Dachuan Zuo, Jingqin Gao, Kaan Ozbay, Zhenning Li. <strong>Informed along the road: roadway capacity driven graph convolution network for network- wide traffic prediction.</strong> Accepted in IEEE Intelligent Transportation Systems Conference (ITSC 2024). <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.13057">link</a></li> <li><strong>Zilin Bian</strong>, Dachuan Zuo, Jingqin Gao and Kaan Ozbay. <strong>Adaptive traffic incident duration prediction: a hybrid approach of change detection and Bayesian network.</strong> Transportmetrica A: Transport Science, under revision.</li> <li><strong>Zilin Bian</strong>, Jingqin Gao, Kaan Ozbay and Zhenning Li. <strong>Traffic prediction considering multiple levels of spatial-temporal information: a multi-scale graph wavelet-based approach</strong> Transportmetrica B: Transport Dynamics, under review. <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.13038">link</a></li> </ul> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="AI"/><category term="operation"/><category term="planning"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI-driven methods to provide traffic impact for immediate, near-future, and long-term period, aiding mobility and incident management process.]]></summary></entry></feed>